[The Epoch of Miyu]
[미유시대]
[Episode 5]
[5화]
Don't be angry.
화내지 마세요.
It's just a job.
그것은 단지 직업일 뿐입니다.
If Yuhua doesn't want you,
Yuhua가 당신을 원하지 않는다면,
that's because of their poor judgment.
그건 그들의 잘못된 판단 때문이다.
It's not your fault at all.
그것은 전혀 당신의 잘못이 아닙니다.
Don't blame yourself.
자신을 비난하지 마십시오.
Stop being angry with yourself.
자신에게 화를 내지 마십시오.
Hang it here.
여기에 걸어두세요.
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
Well...
음...
This... This is...
이건... 이건...
If I knew this would happen,
이런 일이 일어날 줄 알았다면
I shouldn't have forced you at that time.
그때는 강요하지 말았어야 했는데.
Anyway,
어쨌든,
I'm actually the one who hurts myself and others.
사실 내가 바로 그 사람이야 나 자신과 다른 사람에게 상처를 주는 사람.
Right?
오른쪽?
I'm so contemptible, too.
나도 너무 경멸스럽다.
Everything is my fault.
모든 것이 내 잘못입니다.
I'll go back and figure out a way myself.
나는 돌아가서 스스로 길을 찾아볼 것이다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Listen to me.
내 말을 들어보세요.
Let me explain.
설명하겠습니다.
Regarding that outfit,
그 의상에 관해서는
she left it here.
그녀는 그것을 여기에 두고 왔습니다.
I've been busy lately and had no time to tidy up the place.
최근에 바빴어요 장소를 정리할 시간이 없었습니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Don't be angry. Don't be angry.
화내지 마세요. 화내지 마세요.
Don't be angry.
화내지 마세요.
See if there's anything you don't like in the house.
무슨 일이라도 있는지 살펴보세요 당신은 집에 있는 것을 좋아하지 않습니다.
Just throw them all away.
그냥 모두 버리세요.
Okay?
좋아요?
Stop crying.
울지 마세요.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Sit down.
앉으세요.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Stop crying.
울지 마세요.
I've never been fired before.
저는 해고된 적이 없습니다.
It's just a job, isn't it?
그것은 단지 직업일 뿐이죠, 그렇죠?
So what if you got fired?
그럼 해고되면 어떡하지?
At worst, you can just give up working,
최악의 경우에는 일을 포기할 수도 있습니다.
and I'll support you financially.
그리고 나는 당신을 재정적으로 지원할 것입니다.
Do you mean
그 말은
I can stay at home
집에 있을 수 있어
to wash dishes, cook, clean the house
설거지, 요리, 집 청소
and serve you like Xu Miyu?
그리고 Xu Miyu처럼 당신을 섬기나요?
That's actually not what I mean.
실제로 내 말은 그게 아니다.
That's not what I mean.
내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니다.
Don't think like that.
그렇게 생각하지 마세요.
It's good if it's not like that.
그렇지 않으면 좋습니다.
Let me tell you,
말해주지
Nie Yucheng.
니 유청.
If I marry you,
내가 당신과 결혼한다면
I don't want to be the second Xu Miyu.
나는 두 번째 Xu Miyu가되고 싶지 않습니다.
I know. I understand.
알아요. 이해합니다.
Do you think this is okay?
이게 괜찮다고 생각하세요?
I'll go to the travel agency tomorrow
내일 여행사에 갈 거야
to check among all the hotels we're working with,
확인하다 우리가 협력하고 있는 모든 호텔 중에서
which one is better than Yuhua,
어느 것이 Yuhua보다 낫나요?
and I'll select one for you. Okay?
제가 하나를 선택해 드리겠습니다. 좋아요?
So you're happy now?
그럼 지금은 행복해요?
It looks like I'm doing the right thing.
내가 옳은 일을 하고 있는 것 같습니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Don't be angry.
화내지 마세요.
You won't be pretty if you're angry.
화를 내면 예쁘지 않을 것입니다.
Then what are you going to do
그럼 넌 뭘 할 거야
with Xu Miyu's things?
Xu Miyu의 것들로?
I'm going to throw them all away.
나는 그것들을 모두 버릴 것이다.
Is that okay?
괜찮나요?
Alright.
괜찮은.
I think in terms of hotel operations,
호텔 운영 측면에서
we should not only focus on Purong's brand concept,
우리는 뿐만 아니라 푸롱의 브랜드 컨셉에 중점을 두고
[Purong Hotel]
[푸롱 호텔]
but also integrate this brand concept
뿐만 아니라 이 브랜드 컨셉도 통합합니다
into the daily lives of our guests.
손님들의 일상 속으로
Purong represents a classic style of life
푸롱은 고전적인 삶의 방식을 대표합니다
[Purong Hotel]
[푸롱 호텔]
and a kind of top-level dignity.
일종의 최고 수준의 존엄성이죠.
But the foundation of the hotel
하지만 호텔의 기초는
is still to serve the guests
아직 손님 접대 중이야
and the people who live in this city.
그리고 이 도시에 사는 사람들.
Therefore, the important thing
그러므로 중요한 것은
is to link with current trends
현재 트렌드와 연결하는 것
and promote the lifestyle which Purong represents
라이프 스타일을 홍보하고 푸롱이 나타내는 것
to more guests.
더 많은 손님에게.
For example,
예를 들어
we can hold a street pop-up event
거리 팝업 이벤트를 열 수 있어요
with the theme of Purong's
푸롱을 주제로
classic afternoon tea
전형적인 애프터눈 티
so that Purong can enter people's lives
푸롱이 사람들의 삶에 들어갈 수 있도록
in a more accessible way.
더 접근하기 쉬운 방법으로.
Could you tell me if you've had any experience in leading a team before?
혹시 그런 적이 있는지 말해줄 수 있나요? 이전에 팀을 이끌었던 경험이 있나요?
Which hotel did you work for previously?
이전에 어느 호텔에서 일하셨나요?
At...
...
home.
집.
Xu Miyu.
쉬미유.
Don't be frustrated.
좌절하지 마십시오.
Work experience
업무 경험
is just a prerequisite.
단지 전제조건일 뿐입니다.
It can't be helped.
어쩔 수 없습니다.
I know.
알아요.
Actually, you're pretty good.
사실, 당신은 꽤 좋은 사람이에요.
You understand the underlying logic
당신은 기본 논리를 이해하고 있습니다
and also have your own ideas.
그리고 당신만의 아이디어도 가지고 있어요.
It's just that our hotel's threshold has shut you out.
그냥 우리 호텔의 문지방이네 당신을 차단했습니다.
Thank you for acknowledging me.
나를 인정해주셔서 감사합니다.
Wait!
기다리다!
If you really need a job desperately
정말 일자리가 절실히 필요하다면
and also want to engage in the hotel industry,
그리고 또한 싶어 호텔 산업에 종사하다
you may still have a chance for that.
아직 그럴 기회가 있을 수도 있어요.
Starting from the entry-level jobs
초급 작업부터 시작
[Purong Hotel: We welcome you]
[푸롱호텔 : 천만에요]
seems like a detour,
우회하는 것 같은데,
[HSKP Department]
[HSKP 부서]
but actually, it's to take it step by step,
하지만 실제로는 단계별로 진행하는 것입니다.
[F&B Department]
[F&B부]
which might be more down-to-earth.
좀 더 현실적일 수도 있습니다.
What's more, our hotel
게다가 우리 호텔
has exclusively established
has exclusively established
a fast-track promotion channel for our own employees.
패스트트랙 프로모션 채널 우리 직원들을 위해서요.
Entry-level attendants
초급 수행원
also have the opportunity to become general managers.
기회도 갖고 총책임자가 되려면.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Think about it.
생각해 보세요.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
I'm almost there.
거의 다 왔어요.
It'll take about
대략
20 minutes.
20분.
Who are you?
누구세요?
You're going to break my door thoroughly.
당신은 내 문을 완전히 부술 것입니다.
What exactly is your relationship
당신의 관계는 정확히 무엇입니까
with this little scoundrel surnamed Wu?
우라는 이름의 이 작은 악당과 함께?
H-He's my landlord.
H-그 사람은 내 집주인이에요.
He's not your landlord!
그 사람은 당신의 집주인이 아닙니다!
I'm your real landlord.
내가 당신의 진짜 집주인이에요.
He still owes me two months' rent.
그는 아직도 나에게 두 달치 집세를 갚아야 한다.
That's impossible.
그것은 불가능합니다.
I just paid him half a year's rent yesterday.
방금 그 사람한테 돈을 줬어요 어제 반년 집세.
I'll call him and ask about it.
내가 그 사람에게 전화해서 물어볼게.
[Contacts]
[연락처]
[Unknown Caller]
[알 수 없는 발신자]
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Is that Xu Miyu?
그 사람이 쉬미유인가요?
Yes, speaking.
응, 말이야.
Your installment loan of 5,000 yuan for this month
할부 대출 이번 달에는 5,000위안
is about to be overdue.
기한이 지체될 예정입니다.
If you still don't pay,
그래도 비용을 지불하지 않으면
we will take extreme measures.
극단적인 조치를 취하겠습니다.
I got it.
알겠어요.
I'll figure out a way.
제가 방법을 찾아보겠습니다.
Ma'am, my bag is still inside.
부인, 제 가방이 아직 안에 있어요.
We've received your report.
귀하의 신고가 접수되었습니다.
Go home and wait for our notice.
집에 가서 우리의 통지를 기다리십시오.
Officer,
장교,
how long will I have to wait?
얼마나 기다려야 합니까?
I still don't know
아직도 모르겠어요
when the case can be solved.
사건이 해결될 수 있을 때.
We will definitely do our best.
우리는 반드시 최선을 다할 것입니다.
This scoundrel surnamed Wu
Wu라는 이름의 이 악당
took all my and this young lady's money away.
내 전부를 가져갔어 그리고 이 젊은 아가씨는 돈을 잃어버렸어요.
He also stole many of her expensive bags.
그는 또한 그녀의 값비싼 가방을 많이 훔쳤습니다.
Officer,
장교,
you have to arrest and punish the culprits for us.
당신은 체포해야 그리고 우리를 위해 범인을 처벌해주세요.
Yes, yes, yes.
예, 예, 예.
Please calm down.
진정하세요.
This is money,
이건 돈이야,
not orange peels.
오렌지 껍질이 아닙니다.
[Reminder of Consumer Finance Repayment]
[소비자 금융 상환 알림]
[Dear Customer: Tomorrow is your repayment date...]
[친애하는 고객님께: 내일이 상환일인데...]
Take notes of that.
그 점을 기록해 두십시오.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
We'll definitely handle it properly for you.
저희가 꼭 처리해드리겠습니다 당신을 위해 제대로.
[Dad]
[아빠]
Dad, are you asleep?
아빠, 주무셨나요?
[Mom: Inviting You to Voice Chat]
[엄마: 음성채팅에 초대합니다]
[Mom]
[엄마]
Hello, Mom.
안녕하세요, 엄마.
Miyu.
미유.
Why did you call us so late at night?
왜 이렇게 늦은 밤에 우리한테 전화했어요?
Your dad is already asleep.
네 아버지는 이미 주무시고 계세요.
It's about the loan for our guesthouse.
우리 게스트하우스의 대출에 관한 것입니다.
There's still 5,000 yuan to pay this month.
아직 5,000위안 남았네요 이번 달에 지불하기로 했어요.
Can you ask Dad to transfer it to me when he has time?
아빠한테 나한테 전달해달라고 부탁할 수 있어? 그 사람 시간 있으면?
Miyu.
미유.
Did something happen to you?
당신에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Why are you asking your dad for money?
왜 아빠한테 돈을 달라고 하세요?
Well, didn't we agree before?
글쎄, 우리는 전에 동의하지 않았나요?
This money was borrowed under my name,
이 돈은 내 이름으로 빌린 거야,
but after the guesthouse was opened,
하지만 게스트하우스가 문을 연 후에는
we'd use its profits to repay the loan.
우리는 그 이익을 사용하여 대출금을 상환할 것입니다.
Dad promised me.
아빠는 나에게 약속했다.
How come you're so tactless?
왜 그렇게 재치가 없나요?
Xu isn't your biological father.
Xu는 당신의 생물학적 아버지가 아닙니다.
There are things that he can't bring himself to say.
것들이 있어요 그 사람은 차마 말할 수 없다는 걸요.
Let me tell you the truth.
진실을 말하겠습니다.
Since the guesthouse was opened,
게스트하우스가 오픈한 이후
only a few guests have come in dribs and drabs.
손님이 몇 명밖에 안 왔어요 드리블과 드랩에서.
There has been no profit at all.
전혀 이익이 나지 않았습니다.
Your dad has been so worried these few days that he can't sleep well.
아빠가 너무 걱정했어 요즘 그는 잠을 잘 못 자요.
How would he have money to repay the loan?
그 사람은 대출금을 갚을 돈이 어떻게 있었을까요?
Let me ask you.
물어보겠습니다.
Did Nie Yucheng refuse to pay this money?
Nie Yucheng이 이 돈 지불을 거부했습니까?
Everything was fine two months ago.
두 달 전에는 모든 것이 괜찮았습니다.
Are you two still having conflicts?
아직도 둘이 갈등을 겪고 있나요?
Couples don't hold grudges overnight.
부부는 하룻밤 사이에 원한을 품지 않습니다.
If that doesn't work,
그래도 작동하지 않으면
I'll go talk to him.
내가 가서 그 사람이랑 얘기 좀 해볼게.
No.
아니요.
Don't overthink it.
지나치게 생각하지 마십시오.
It's good if it's not like that.
그렇지 않으면 좋습니다.
Just give him a chance
그에게 기회를 주세요
to make up for his mistakes.
그의 실수를 만회하기 위해.
Ask him to treat you better in the future.
앞으로는 더 잘 대해달라고 부탁하세요.
I'm doing this for your own good.
나는 당신의 이익을 위해 이 일을 하고 있습니다.
You've been good-tempered with a gentle personality since childhood.
성격이 좋으셨어요 어릴 때부터 온순한 성격을 가지고 있다.
I'm afraid you'll suffer losses.
나는 당신이 손실을 입을 까봐 두렵습니다.
Got it?
알았어요?
Rest early then.
그럼 일찍 쉬세요.
I'm hanging up.
전화를 끊습니다.
Starting from the entry-level jobs
초급 작업부터 시작
seems like a detour,
우회하는 것 같은데,
but actually, it's to take it step by step,
하지만 실제로는 단계별로 진행하는 것입니다.
which might be more down-to-earth.
좀 더 현실적일 수도 있습니다.
What's more, our hotel has exclusively established
게다가, 저희 호텔은 독점적으로 설립되었습니다
a fast-track promotion channel for our own employees.
패스트트랙 프로모션 채널 우리 직원들을 위해서요.
Entry-level attendants
초급 수행원
also have the opportunity to become general managers.
기회도 갖고 총책임자가 되려면.
[Contacts]
[연락처]
[Qiaoqi]
[차오치]
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Are you hiring attendants right now?
지금 승무원을 채용하고 있나요?
Yes, we are. Have you ever worked as a cleaner before?
예, 그렇습니다. 이전에 청소부로 일해 본 적이 있나요?
No, I haven't.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
But I've been a housewife for 10 years.
하지만 저는 10년 동안 주부였습니다.
I'm very good at tidying up rooms.
나는 방 정리를 아주 잘해요.
What's more, I've had an interview at Purong before.
게다가, 예전에 푸롱에서 인터뷰를 한 적이 있어요.
The interviewer recommended me to apply for this job.
면접관 나에게 이 직업에 지원하라고 권유했어요.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Bring your ID card
신분증을 지참하세요
and report for duty on the B2 floor in the staff area during working hours.
지하 2층에서 근무보고를 합니다. 근무 시간 동안 직원 구역에서.
Do you provide meals and accommodation?
식사와 숙소를 제공하나요?
Yes, we do.
네, 그렇습니다.
We have dorms.
우리에겐 기숙사가 있습니다.
Can I go today?
오늘 갈 수 있나요?
Yes, you can.
예, 가능합니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Then I'll report for duty today.
그럼 오늘은 출근하겠습니다.
[Purong Hotel: Staff Entrance]
[푸롱 호텔: 직원 입구]
Don't block the way at the entrance.
입구에서 길을 막지 마세요.
Step aside!
물러서세요!
Come on! This way!
어서 해봐요! 이쪽으로!
Be careful!
조심하세요!
Come on! Watch out!
어서 해봐요! 조심하세요!
Come on! Let's go!
어서 해봐요! 갑시다!
Make way, please!
비켜주세요!
Come on! This way!
어서 해봐요! 이쪽으로!
Come on! Step aside!
어서 해봐요! 물러서세요!
Hurry up!
서둘러요!
Are you a newcomer here?
당신은 여기에 새로 온 사람입니까?
Yes.
예.
My name's Xu Miyu.
내 이름은 Xu Miyu입니다.
Come on. Follow me.
어서 해봐요. 나를 따르라.
The forewoman is waiting for you.
여주인공이 당신을 기다리고 있습니다.
Ms. Zhang! Ms. Zhang!
장 씨! 장 씨!
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
The guest in Room 1821 wants to change to another room.
1821호실의 손님 다른 방으로 바꾸고 싶어요.
It's that Black Card Ji again.
또 그 블랙카드 지입니다.
Let him stay wherever he wants.
그가 원하는 곳에 머물게 해주세요.
But we are short-handed right now.
하지만 지금 우리는 일손이 부족합니다.
I'll ask someone to clean the room.
누군가에게 방 청소를 부탁하겠습니다.
You guys should go handle the guest now.
너희들은 지금 가서 손님을 맞이해야 한다.
Madam Cailu!
카일루 부인!
Are you in there?
당신은 거기에 있습니까?
Who is it?
누구입니까?
It's me.
나야.
Well, what are you doing here?
글쎄, 여기서 뭐하는거야?
I brought the newcomer here for you.
나는 당신을 위해 새로 온 사람을 여기로 데려왔습니다.
It's dusty here.
여기는 먼지가 많습니다.
Let's talk outside.
밖에서 얘기하자
Let me introduce myself.
제 소개를 할게요.
My name's Zhang Cailu.
제 이름은 장카일루입니다.
I'm the forewoman of the executive floor.
저는 집행부의 주임입니다.
Hello, Ms. Zhang.
안녕하세요, 장씨.
I'm Xu Miyu.
저는 쉬미유(Xu Miyu)입니다.
Your hands are quite soft.
당신의 손은 꽤 부드럽습니다.
You've never worked before, huh?
당신은 한 번도 일해 본 적이 없군요, 그렇죠?
I've done housework at home.
집에서 집안일을 했어요.
You are 35 years old now.
당신은 이제 35세입니다.
Age is not a problem.
나이는 문제가 되지 않습니다.
Take your time.
천천히 시간을 가지세요.
Yin Xiang.
인샹.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Take Miyu upstairs
미유를 위층으로 데려가
and clean Room 1821.
그리고 클린룸 1821호.
Consider it as training.
훈련이라고 생각하세요.
Don't you want the training allowance?
훈련수당을 원하지 않나요?
Yes, I do!
예, 그렇습니다!
This way. That room.
이쪽으로. 그 방.
The room at the end.
마지막에 있는 방.
Just leave the cart here.
카트는 여기에 놔두시면 됩니다.
Take the vacuum cleaner with you.
진공청소기를 가지고 가세요.
The vacuum cleaner.
진공청소기.
Okay.
좋아요.
Luckily, it's not an extremely messy scene.
다행히도, 그다지 지저분한 장면은 아닙니다.
Let me tell you.
내가 당신에게 말해 보자.
Opening a hotel room door
호텔 방 문 열기
is like opening a blind box.
블라인드 박스를 여는 것과 같습니다.
You'll never know
넌 절대 모를 거야
what kind of mess the guests left inside.
손님이 내부에 어떤 종류의 난장판을 남겼는지.
A couple of days ago, a woman came here
며칠 전 한 여자가 여기로 왔어요
and gorged on seafood and alcohol in her room.
해산물과 술을 잔뜩 먹었어요 그녀의 방에서.
You have no idea
넌 전혀 몰라
how messy she made the room look.
그녀가 방을 얼마나 지저분하게 만들었는지.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
Mr. Ji,
지 선생님,
please have a rest.
휴식을 취해주세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
[Shampoo]
[샴푸]
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Hello. How can I help...
안녕하세요. 어떻게 도와드릴까요...
I want to change to another room.
다른 방으로 바꾸고 싶어요.
Make this flush.
이것을 플러시하세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Then fold it down.
그런 다음 접으십시오.
Fold this inside,
이것을 안으로 접어서
leaving a corner.
모퉁이를 떠납니다.
Like this.
이와 같이.
Then lift this back up.
그런 다음 이것을 다시 들어 올리십시오.
Watch carefully.
주의 깊게 관찰하세요.
[Hairdryer Bag]
[헤어드라이어 가방]
The hairdryer,
헤어드라이어,
shower caps,
샤워캡,
nail files,
네일 파일,
hair ties,
머리끈,
toothbrushes,
칫솔,
combs
빗
and hand cream are all here.
핸드크림도 다 여기 있어요.
Soap. Remember all of this.
비누. 이 모든 것을 기억하십시오.
If the left-and-right order
왼쪽 오른쪽 순서
of these items in the drawer is wrong,
서랍에 있는 항목 중 잘못된 항목이 있습니다.
you'll get scolded.
당신은 혼날 것입니다.
Replenish two toothbrushes.
칫솔 2개를 보충하세요.
Coming.
오는.
One is enough.
하나면 충분합니다.
This hand cream is used up.
이 핸드크림은 다 써버렸어요.
Replenish a tube of handcream.
핸드크림 튜브를 보충하세요.
Yin Xiang,
음향,
clean up Room 1813.
1813호실을 청소하세요.
Why is there another room?
왜 방이 하나 더 있지?
Isn't Room 1813 empty?
1813호실은 비어있지 않나요?
The guest in Room 1812 changed to it.
1812호실의 손님이 그 방으로 바뀌었습니다.
Now he wants a change again.
이제 그는 다시 변화를 원합니다.
Copy that.
복사하세요.
This kind of guest
이런 손님
is the hardest to deal with.
대처하기가 가장 어렵습니다.
If you don't meet their expectations even slightly,
그렇지 않으면 그들의 기대에 조금이라도 부응하면
they will give you a bad review.
그들은 당신에게 나쁜 평가를 줄 것입니다.
Oh, by the way,
아, 그런데,
you have to be careful from now on.
지금부터 조심해야 합니다.
Getting three bad reviews means you will be fired.
나쁜 리뷰 3개 받기 당신이 해고될 것이라는 뜻이다.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Hello, room service.
안녕하세요, 룸서비스입니다.
It can't be helped. The guest complained, so we have to clean it again.
어쩔 수 없습니다. 손님이 불평을 하더군요. 그래서 다시 청소해야 해요.
A bit further there... further back.
조금 더 멀리... 더 뒤로.
Wipe the right side again.
오른쪽을 다시 닦아주세요.
Here?
여기?
The right. Yes.
권리. 예.
It's almost done. Clean the tea table.
거의 다 끝났습니다. 티 테이블을 청소하세요.
Yin Xiang! Yin Xiang!
인샹! 인샹!
Let me tell you.
내가 당신에게 말해 보자.
He's so handsome. Super handsome.
그는 너무 잘생겼어요. 정말 잘생겼어요.
That incredible jawline.
그 놀라운 턱선.
So handsome.
너무 잘생겼어요.
A newcomer?
새로 온 사람?
My apprentice.
내 견습생.
Miyu, this is...
미유, 이건...
Ke Wenxue.
Ke Wenxue.
Hello, my name's Xu Miyu.
안녕하세요, 제 이름은 Xu Miyu입니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
How come I feel you look a bit familiar to me?
내 기분이 어때서? 너 나 좀 낯익어 보여?
How come I feel I've seen you somewhere?
어째서 당신을 어딘가에서 본 것 같은 느낌이 드는 걸까요?
Have we met before?
우리 전에 만난 적 있나요?
Everyone looks familiar to you.
모두가 당신에게 친숙해 보입니다.
Let's go. It's time to be off work.
갑시다. 이제 퇴근할 시간이다.
If we don't get off work now, the guest might want to change rooms again later.
지금 우리가 퇴근하지 않으면 손님이 나중에 다시 방을 바꾸고 싶을 수도 있습니다.
This way.
이쪽으로.
I just feel like I've seen her before.
방금 전에 그녀를 본 것 같은 느낌이 듭니다.
Miyu,
미유,
this is your dorm.
여기가 네 기숙사야.
Remember this door.
이 문을 기억하세요.
You can sleep on this bed.
이 침대에서 자면 됩니다.
Thank you, Ms. Zhang.
고마워요, 장 씨.
You're welcome.
천만에요.
Rest early.
일찍 쉬세요.
I'm leaving now.
나는 지금 떠난다.
Okay.
좋아요.
It's true, huh?
사실이에요, 그렇죠?
It really costs over 2,000 yuan.
실제로는 2,000위안이 넘는 비용이 듭니다.
Well, if she's using such an expensive suitcase,
글쎄, 그녀가 사용하고 있다면 이렇게 비싼 여행가방이라니
why is she working here as an attendant?
그 사람은 왜 여기서 직원으로 일하고 있는 거야?
Maybe she went bankrupt.
어쩌면 그녀는 파산했을 수도 있습니다.
Otherwise, maybe she was dumped by her husband.
그렇지 않으면, 어쩌면 그녀는 남편에게 버림받았을지도 모릅니다.
Look. She's so much older than us.
바라보다. 그 사람은 우리보다 나이가 훨씬 많아요.
She must have been married before.
그 사람은 전에 결혼한 게 틀림없어요.
Also look at her figure and temperament.
또한 그녀의 모습과 기질을 살펴보십시오.
When Yin Xiang walked with her during the daytime today,
Yin Xiang이 그녀와 함께 걸을 때 오늘 낮에는
she looked like a little maid.
그녀는 작은 하녀처럼 보였습니다.
This is really crazy.
이건 정말 미친짓이다.
Even the middle class is coming to compete with us in this industry.
중산층도 찾아오고 이 업계에서 우리와 경쟁하세요.
Sit.
앉다.
♪ Face the wind ♪
♪ 바람을 바라보세요 ♪
♪ Defeat the wind ♪
♪ 바람을 물리쳐라 ♪
Be quiet!
조용히 하세요!
♪ If time could be slower ♪
♪ 시간이 더 느려질 수 있다면 ♪
-♪ I'll be closer to expectations ♪ -I'm taking listening tests.
-♪기대에 더 가까워지도록 할게요♪ - 듣기 시험을 보고 있어요.
Can you keep your voice down?
목소리 좀 낮춰줄 수 있어?
Ms. Luo,
루오 씨,
this is a dorm, not a classroom.
여기는 교실이 아니라 기숙사예요.
If you think this is noisy, go to the study room.
시끄럽다고 생각되신다면, 공부방으로 가세요.
How ill-mannered.
얼마나 매너가 나쁜지.
Although I was tired today,
오늘은 피곤했지만
at least, I got to see a handsome guy.
적어도 잘생긴 남자는 만나야지.
You enjoyed looking at the handsome guy
잘생긴 남자를 보는 게 즐거웠어요
while we were exhausted today.
오늘 우리가 지쳤을 때.
Keep your voice down.
목소리를 낮추세요.
I remember now.
이제 기억나네요.
The newcomer who came today
오늘 새로 온 사람
was that rich woman who ate and drank a lot
그 부자 여자였어? 많이 먹고 마신 사람
alone in Room 1816 that day.
그날 1816호실에 혼자 있었습니다.
Why did she come here?
그녀는 왜 여기에 왔나요?
I couldn't have made a mistake.
나는 실수를 할 수 없었습니다.
If there was a mistake, the receptionists must have assigned them wrongly.
실수가 있었다면 접수원이 잘못 할당했을 것입니다.
Now that a mistake has been made,
이제 실수가 발생했으니
switch them back at once.
즉시 다시 전환해 보세요.
I'm busy right now.
나는 지금 바쁘다.
I still have a pile of guests' dry-cleaned clothes to fold.
아직 한가득 있어요 손님들의 드라이클리닝된 옷을 접어주세요.
Miyu.
미유.
You're here just in time.
당신은 시간에 맞춰 여기에 왔습니다.
Yin Xiang mixed up the takeout for two rooms.
인 시앙 두 방의 테이크아웃을 섞었습니다.
The lobby clerks mixed them up.
로비 직원이 그들을 뒤섞었습니다.
Do me a favor.
부탁 좀 해주세요.
Make adjustments between the two sides.
양쪽 사이를 조정합니다.
If the guests need anything, try to satisfy them.
손님에게 필요한 것이 있으면 그들을 만족시키려고 노력하세요.
Go fold the clothes now.
지금 가서 옷을 개세요.
Thank you both.
둘 다 감사합니다.
Thanks for your help.
도움을 주셔서 감사합니다.
I'm sorry, sir.
죄송합니다.
We made a mistake just now.
방금 실수를 했습니다.
I'm here to switch your takeout.
테이크아웃 메뉴를 바꾸려고 왔어요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Room service.
룸서비스.
I'm sorry, sir.
죄송합니다.
-I'm here to switch your take- -This is outrageous.
-당신의 생각을 바꾸러 왔습니다- -이건 터무니없는 일이군요.
How come it's you?
왜 당신이에요?
You are...
당신은...
I sincerely apologize.
진심으로 사과드립니다.
This is our oversight.
이것은 우리의 감독입니다.
It was caused by our staff's careless cleaning.
발생한 것이다 저희 직원의 부주의한 청소로 인해
We'll definitely deal with this seriously.
우리는 이 문제를 반드시 진지하게 다룰 것입니다.
However, regarding this matter,
그러나 이 문제와 관련하여
we've already investigated it thoroughly.
우리는 이미 그것을 철저히 조사했습니다.
It's entirely our hotel's responsibility,
그것은 전적으로 우리 호텔의 책임입니다.
so you can rest assured, Mrs. Nie.
그러니 안심하세요, 니에 부인.
Miyu,
미유,
how is the adjustment going?
조정은 어떻게 진행되고 있나요?
I...
나는...
I haven't...
난...
How about this?
이건 어때요?
The guest in Room 1822
1822호실의 손님
has already ordered at the Chinese restaurant.
이미 주문했습니다 중국 식당에서.
Now the key is that the guest in Room 1812
이제 핵심은 1812호실의 손님이
is a bit difficult to deal with.
다루기가 좀 어렵습니다.
I will go talk to him.
나는 그에게 가서 이야기할 것이다.
I can handle it.
나는 그것을 처리할 수 있다.
[Do Not Disturb]
[방해하지 마세요]
Now that's all for the takeout incident from last night.
이제 그게 다야 어젯밤 테이크아웃 사건 때문에요.
Luckily, the guests let it slide.
운 좋게도 손님이 미끄러지도록 내버려 두었습니다.
Let's just move on.
계속 진행합시다.
Luo Qingping,
루오칭핑,
you are in charge of Room 1812 today.
당신은 오늘 1812호실을 담당하고 있습니다.
I'm not going to Room 1812.
나는 1812호실에 가지 않을 거예요.
Are you afraid of getting a bad review?
나쁜 평가를 받을까 봐 두렵나요?
Aren't you afraid of that?
그게 두렵지 않나요?
If not, you can go.
그렇지 않다면 가셔도 됩니다.
I've been there.
나는 거기에 있었다.
We've all been there.
우리 모두 거기에 가본 적이 있어요.
You are the only one who hasn't.
당신은 그렇지 않은 유일한 사람입니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Stop arguing, everyone.
다들 그만 논쟁하세요.
Let's take turns.
교대로 해보자.
Luo Qingping,
루오칭핑,
you're the most capable one on our floor.
당신은 우리 층에서 가장 유능한 사람입니다.
Go show him what you can do
가서 당신이 무엇을 할 수 있는지 보여주세요
so that he can't find any fault with it.
그래서 그는 그것에서 어떤 결점도 찾을 수 없습니다.
Even the most capable person shouldn't be treated like this, huh?
가장 유능한 사람이라도 이런 취급을 받아서는 안 되지, 응?
Last time, I was also the one who handled the weirdo
저번에도 나도 그랬는데 그 이상한 사람을 처리한 사람
who wanted his socks to be hand-washed.
양말을 손으로 빨기를 원했던 사람.
And before that,
그리고 그 전에
that family of five with three sons
세 아들을 둔 다섯 식구
was served by me from beginning to end, too.
나한테 서빙됐어 그것도 처음부터 끝까지.
Madam Cailu, you just can't cherish elites in this way, huh?
카일루 부인, 당신은 그럴 수 없어요 이런 식으로 엘리트를 소중히 여기죠?
I'll go.
나는 갈 것이다.
Hello, I'm the attendant for the room cleaning service.
안녕하세요, 저는 수행자입니다 객실 청소 서비스를 위해
Hello, I'm Xu Miyu from the HSKP Department.
안녕하세요 쑤미유 입니다 HSKP학과 출신입니다.
I'm responsible for cleaning your room today.
나는 책임이 있다 오늘 네 방 청소를 위해.
May I come in?
들어가도 될까요?
Yes.
예.
Are you going to stand here
여기 서실 건가요
to supervise my work?
내 일을 감독하려고?
Mr. Ji.
지 씨.
Do you need me to change the bedding for you?
내가 필요합니까? 침구를 갈아 주려고?
You can decide. Thank you.
당신은 결정할 수 있습니다. 감사합니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
It's not necessary. Thanks.
그것은 필요하지 않습니다. 감사해요.
You don't need to change it.
변경할 필요가 없습니다.
That's not okay.
그건 옳지 않아요.
I have to help you
당신을 도와야 해요
change it thoroughly,
철저하게 바꾸세요,
from top to bottom,
위에서 아래로,
from left to right
왼쪽에서 오른쪽으로
and from the inside to the outside.
그리고 내부에서 외부로.
Otherwise,
그렇지 않으면
if the previous guest
이전 손님인 경우
left something indecent here
여기에 음란한 걸 남겼어
and you want to blame it on me,
그리고 당신은 그것을 나에게 비난하고 싶어
I won't be able to explain it.
나는 그것을 설명할 수 없을 것이다.
Mr. Ji,
지 선생님,
are you always such a helpful man?
당신은 항상 그렇게 도움이 되는 사람인가요?
Whenever you see someone in trouble,
누군가 곤경에 처해 있는 것을 볼 때마다
you just can't help lending a hand.
당신은 도움을 줄 수 없습니다.
Even if it means covering up scandals for others,
뜻이라 해도 다른 사람을 위해 스캔들을 은폐하고
you still won't hesitate to do it.
당신은 여전히 ​​​​그것을 주저하지 않을 것입니다.
Why are you here,
왜 여기에 있나요?
Mrs. Nie?
니에 부인?
Thanks to you,
고마워요
I am no longer Mrs. Nie now.
나는 이제 더 이상 니에 부인이 아닙니다.
I...
나는...
I think there might be some misunderstanding between us.
내 생각엔 좀 있을 수도 있을 것 같아 우리 사이의 오해.
Is there a misunderstanding?
오해가 있나요?
You helped my ex-husband lie to me last time.
당신은 내 전남편을 도왔습니다 지난번에 나한테 거짓말을 했어.
Have you forgotten that so quickly?
그걸 너무 빨리 잊었나요?
If my previous service
내 이전 서비스가
caused you any unpleasant experience,
불쾌한 경험을 하게 되었어요
I sincerely apologize to you.
진심으로 사과드립니다.
But if I'm not mistaken,
하지만 내가 착각한 것이 아니라면
it's your working time now.
지금은 근무 시간이에요.
Do the attendants at Purong Hotel
푸롱 호텔의 승무원을 수행
all like to chat while working?
다들 일하면서 채팅하는 걸 좋아하시나요?
I need to take a call.
전화를 받아야 해요.
Take your time to clean the room.
시간을 내어 방을 청소하십시오.
Andrew.
앤드류.
Yeah, sure.
응, 물론이지.
I'm not doing anything important right now.
난 안 하고 있어 지금 당장 중요한 것.
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
Ms. Zhang,
장 씨,
are you looking for me?
나를 찾고 있나요?
Close the door.
문을 닫으세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Let me ask you something.
한 가지 물어보겠습니다.
When you cleaned
청소했을 때
Room 1812,
1812호실,
was the guest there?
손님이 거기 있었나요?
Yes.
예.
Did this guest
이 손님이 있었나요
pick on you to your face
pick on you to your face
and deliberately make things difficult for you?
그리고 의도적으로 일을 어렵게 만들어?
Tell me the details
세부사항을 말해줘
so that I can warn the other girls
다른 여자들에게 경고할 수 있도록
not to get in his way.
그의 길을 방해하지 않도록.
He didn't make things difficult for me.
그 사람은 나를 힘들게 하지 않았어요.
He really didn't?
정말 그렇지 않았나요?
You have no idea
넌 전혀 몰라
how badly Jia got scolded when she came back that day.
지아가 얼마나 심하게 혼났는지 그 날 그녀가 돌아왔을 때.
He said it was unprofessional for her to wear perfume.
그는 그것이 그녀에게 비전문적이라고 말했다 향수를 뿌리려고.
Actually, the young girl just loved being pretty,
사실 그 어린 소녀는 그냥 예쁜 게 좋았어
and her perfume was a bit strong.
그리고 그녀의 향수가 좀 강했어요.
It was as if she had stabbed him in the nose.
마치 그녀가 그를 찔렀던 것 같았어요 코에.
Then he just gave her a bad review.
그런 다음 그는 그녀에게 나쁜 평가를 했습니다.
Did he...
그 사람이...
also give me a bad review?
나한테도 나쁜 평가를 줘?
He didn't give you a bad review.
그는 당신에게 나쁜 평가를 하지 않았습니다.
Encountering weird guests like Black Card Ji,
이상한 손님을 만나다 블랙카드 지처럼
we attendants tend to suffer the most.
우리 승무원이 가장 고통받는 경향이 있습니다.
But we can only endure the suffering.
하지만 우리는 고통을 견딜 수 밖에 없습니다.
So we have to share information with each other
그러니까 정보를 공유해야지 서로
to avoid pitfalls.
함정을 피하기 위해.
Got it?
알았어요?
Got it.
알았어요.
Ms. Zhang,
장 씨,
why do you all call him Black Card Ji?
왜 다들 블랙카드 지라고 부르나요?
You don't know this?
당신은 이것을 몰라?
Our hotel's top-tier VIP card
우리 호텔의 최고급 VIP 카드
is a black card made of graphite.
흑연으로 만든 검은색 카드입니다.
There are only three in total.
총 3개밖에 없습니다.
And that Mr. Ji has one.
그리고 지씨가 하나 가지고 있어요.
This person...
이 사람은...
is that powerful?
그게 강력해요?
This guy
이 사람
definitely has a strong background.
확실히 강력한 배경이 있습니다.
He's holding a black card
그는 검은색 카드를 들고 있어
and staying on our executive floor.
그리고 우리 이그제큐티브 플로어에 머무르세요.
If he says someone is good or bad,
그가 누군가가 좋다 나쁘다라고 말하면
his word carries much more weight than that of the others.
그의 말은 훨씬 더 큰 무게를 지닌다 다른 사람들보다.
You must remember
기억해야 해
not to provoke him.
그를 자극하지 않기 위해서입니다.
Ms. Zhang,
장 씨,
the guest in Room 1815
1815호실의 손님
is calling for service.
서비스를 요청하고 있습니다.
Copy that.
복사하세요.
Coming right up.
바로 올라옵니다.
Go to Room 1815.
1815호실로 가세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Can't you see that?
그걸 볼 수 없나요?
Pick them up now!
지금 바로 픽업하세요!
Okay.
좋아요.
I don't even know if you guys understand.
나도 모르겠어 너희들이 이해한다면.
Come on. Here you are.
어서 해봐요. 여기 있어요.
Are they arranged in order?
순서대로 배열되어 있나요?
Are you a newcomer?
당신은 새로 온 사람입니까?
What's your name?
이름이 뭐에요?
My name is Xu Miyu.
제 이름은 쉬미유입니다.
Go away.
저리 가요.
Don't bother me.
나를 괴롭히지 마십시오.
Okay.
좋아요.
Miyu.
미유.
You're not the only one that's afraid of him.
당신은 유일한 사람이 아니다 그게 그를 두려워하는 것입니다.
We're all afraid of him.
우리는 모두 그를 두려워합니다.
I've heard
들었어
that old man is a writer.
그 노인은 작가예요.
When he's in a good mood,
기분이 좋을 때
he acts like a normal person.
그는 평범한 사람처럼 행동합니다.
But when he has writer's block, he'll just scold others.
하지만 작가의 블록이 있으면 그는 다른 사람들을 꾸짖을 것입니다.
Whoever has to deal with
누구를 상대해야 하는가
a guy like that is just unlucky.
그런 사람은 그냥 운이 없는 사람이에요.
I actually think this kind of person is easier to get along with.
사실 이런 사람인 것 같아요 함께 지내기가 더 쉽습니다.
They don't give bad reviews indiscriminately.
그들은 나쁜 리뷰를 주지 않는다 무차별적으로.
They're much better than Black Card Ji.
블랙카드지보다 훨씬 낫네요.
That's easy for you to say.
당신이 말하는 것은 쉽습니다.
Why didn't you go then?
그때 왜 안 갔어?
Ke Wenxue.
Ke Wenxue.
Just put all this chattering energy into your work performance.
그냥 이 수다스러운 에너지를 다 쏟아부어 당신의 업무 성과에.
Aren't you just so envious of me for having no bad reviews?
너 내가 너무 부러워하는 거 아니야? 나쁜 리뷰가 없어서요?
Let's switch rooms and you can try it.
방을 바꿔서 시도해 보세요.
Let's switch then.
그럼 전환해 보겠습니다.
Stop arguing.
논쟁을 멈추세요.
Let's all try not to get any bad reviews.
우리 모두 나쁜 평가를 받지 않도록 노력합시다.
We don't need you to be the peacemaker here.
우리는 당신이 필요하지 않습니다 여기서 평화를 이루는 사람이 되십시오.
Except me, you're the only one here who hasn't gotten a bad review.
나 빼고 여기엔 너뿐이야 나쁜 평가를 받지 않은 사람.
That's just because you haven't been here for long.
바로 그 이유야 당신은 여기에 오래 있지 않았습니다.
Let's see how much longer you can hang in.
얼마나 더 버틸 수 있는지 볼까요.
Room 1815 needs room service.
1815호실에는 룸서비스가 필요합니다.
I'll help you clean up later.
나중에 청소하는 것을 도와드릴게요.
Just go now.
지금 가세요.
Coming.
오는.
Don't interrupt my train of thought.
내 생각의 흐름을 방해하지 마십시오.
Engineering Department.
엔지니어링 부서.
Is anyone there now?
지금 거기 누구 있어요?
The light in Room 1815 is broken.
1815호실의 조명이 깨졌습니다.
Copy that.
복사하세요.
Is it this late already?
벌써 이렇게 늦었나요?
Xu Miyu.
쉬미유.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Come here and take a look at this passage.
여기 와서 이 구절을 살펴보세요.
Look. What do you think of this part?
바라보다. 이 부분에 대해서는 어떻게 생각하시나요?
[He put on that ring on the wedding day.]
[그는 결혼식 날 그 반지를 꼈다.]
[The wedding was simple and plain, with no grand ceremony.]
[결혼식은 단순하고 평범했지만, 성대한 예식은 없습니다.]
[Nor were there any romantic vows.]
[낭만적인 서약도 없었습니다.]
It's well written.
잘 쓰여졌네요.
Does it show
보여요
the hidden pain
숨겨진 고통
in Tingsheng's heart?
Tingsheng의 마음에?
Come on. Look at that ring.
어서 해봐요. 저 반지 좀 보세요.
I added it on purpose.
일부러 추가했습니다.
[He put on that ring on the wedding day.]
[그는 결혼식 날 그 반지를 꼈다.]
[The wedding was simple and plain, with no grand ceremony.]
[결혼식은 단순하고 평범했지만, 성대한 예식은 없습니다.]
[Nor were there any romantic vows.]
[낭만적인 서약도 없었습니다.]
I just want to make it impossible
난 그냥 불가능하게 만들고 싶을 뿐이야
to take off that ring.
그 반지를 빼려고.
Since he can't take it off,
그는 그것을 벗을 수 없기 때문에
he won't be able to resist
그는 저항할 수 없을 거야
that betrothal.
그 약혼자.
Isn't it wonderful?
정말 멋지지 않나요?
Yes, it is.
예, 그렇습니다.
With your mention of that, I've noticed it, too.
당신이 그 점을 언급하면서, 나도 그것을 알아 차렸다.
Adding the ring as a prop
반지를 소품으로 추가하기
is such a wonderful detail.
정말 멋진 디테일이에요.
If you can even notice that,
그걸 눈치채셨다면,
the editor
편집자
can't possibly say he's unable to notice it, huh?
도저히 말할 수 없다 그 사람은 그걸 눈치채지 못하는 것 같죠?
They will definitely notice it.
그들은 분명히 그것을 알아차릴 것입니다.
If they can't notice it,
눈치채지 못한다면
they must be blind.
그들은 장님이 틀림없어요.
You can leave now.
지금 떠나셔도 됩니다.
No need to clean the room.
방을 청소할 필요가 없습니다.
I'll stay here to wait for the Engineering Department
나는 여기에 머물 것이다 엔지니어링 부서를 기다리다
to repair this light.
이 조명을 수리하기 위해.
Just ignore it. You may go.
그냥 무시하세요. 당신은 갈 수 있습니다.
Is the attendant-on-duty of the executive floor there?
당직근무자인가 거기 중역층에서요?
Room 1803 is pressing for the supper.
1803호실은 저녁 식사를 준비하고 있습니다.
Copy that.
복사하세요.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Good night then.
그럼 잘 자요.
Thanks.
감사해요.
You're welcome.
천만에요.
Sir, did you enjoy your stay these past few days?
선생님, 즐거운 시간 보내셨나요? 지난 며칠 동안?
Please sign here.
여기에 서명해주세요.
Could I take a minute of your time
잠시 시간을 내주시겠어요
to write a review on our HSKP Department
HSKP 학과에 대한 리뷰를 작성해 주세요
so that it can help our hotel improve?
우리 호텔을 개선하는 데 도움이 되도록요?
Sure.
확신하는.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Have you finished reading it?
다 읽으셨나요?
This time,
이번에는
you have to pay me extra money
나에게 추가 비용을 지불해야 해
for the costs of rush work
급한 작업 비용을 지불하기 위해
and supper.
그리고 저녁.
Wait!
기다리다!
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
I wrote for you for over half a month,
반달 넘게 당신을 위해 글을 썼어요
and you just quit with one word?
그런데 딱 한 마디로 그만뒀어?
Refund?
환불하다?
In your dreams!
당신의 꿈에서!
Why are you standing there like a log?
왜 거기 통나무처럼 서 있는 거야?
Do you think I'm such a laughingstock?
내가 그렇게 웃음거리라고 생각하시나요?
I'm sorry, sir.
죄송합니다.
There was nothing to eat.
먹을 것이 없었습니다.
[Guest Satisfaction Survey]
[고객 만족도 조사]
And no one repaired the broken light.
그리고 아무도 깨진 빛을 수리하지 않았습니다.
How could there be such a five-star hotel?
어떻게 이런 5성급 호텔이 있을 수 있었을까요?
Take it to your boss, idiot!
상사에게 가져가라, 바보야!
Ms. Zhang, are you looking for me?
장 씨, 저를 찾고 계시나요?
[Xu Miyu, 18th Floor, Morning Shift, Bad Review]
[쉬미유, 18층, 아침 교대, 나쁜 검토]
When did I get a bad review?
언제 나쁜 평가를 받았나요?
It's all because of that grumpy old man in Room 1815.
다 때문이야 1815호실에 있는 그 심술궂은 노인.
He wrote some garbage
그 사람이 쓰레기 같은 글을 썼어
and got his draft rejected,
초안이 거부됐어요
so he vented his anger all on us.
그래서 그는 우리 모두에게 분노를 표출했습니다.
He cursed the whole hotel from top to bottom.
그는 호텔 전체를 저주했다 위에서 아래로.
We're really so unlucky.
우리는 정말 운이 좋지 않습니다.
But this bad review
그런데 이 나쁜 리뷰
isn't directed at me.
나를 향한 것이 아닙니다.
Miyu,
미유,
here's the thing.
여기에 문제가 있습니다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Take a look.
보세요.
She and she...
그녀와 그녀는...
Neither of them are good enough.
둘 다 충분하지 않습니다.
They can barely protect themselves.
그들은 거의 자신을 보호할 수 없습니다.
So you'll have to take the hit.
그래서 당신은 타격을 받아야 할 것입니다.
I have my difficulties, too.
나에게도 어려움이 있습니다.
If I get two more bad reviews,
나쁜 리뷰를 두 개 더 받으면
I'll be done for.
난 이제 끝이야
Don't be nervous.
긴장하지 마세요.
Let me tell you a secret.
한 가지 비밀을 말씀드리겠습니다.
Even if you get three bad reviews,
나쁜 리뷰 세 개를 받아도
the hotel won't fire you.
호텔은 당신을 해고하지 않을 것입니다.
Really?
정말?
They'll just deduct your bonuses at most.
그들은 기껏해야 보너스를 공제할 것입니다.
How much?
얼마나 많이?
All of it, for sure.
물론 그 모든 것입니다.
You think he'd go easy on you?
그 사람이 당신을 쉽게 대할 것 같나요?
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
If you get another bad review,
또 나쁜 평가를 받으면,
I'll also find someone to remove it for you.
나도 누군가를 찾아볼게 당신을 위해 그것을 제거합니다.
Just do each other a favor.
서로에게 호의를 베풀기만 하면 됩니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
You need to eat more.
더 많이 먹어야합니다.
Take good care of your health.
건강 잘 관리하세요.
[Longevity, Happy Birthday to My Dear Mother]
[장수, 사랑하는 어머니의 생일을 축하드립니다]
Wensi Tofu. All the dishes have been served.
웬시 두부. 모든 요리가 제공되었습니다.
Please enjoy your meal.
맛있게 드시기 바랍니다.
[Longevity, Happy Birthday to My Dear Mother]
[장수, 사랑하는 어머니의 생일을 축하드립니다]
To celebrate this birthday today,
오늘 생일을 축하하기 위해
I'm really so happy.
정말 너무 행복해요.
My son is successful in his career,
내 아들은 경력에서 성공하고 있어요
and my daughter-in-law even brought our family a grandson.
그리고 내 며느리 심지어 우리 가족에게 손자를 데려왔습니다.
I am completely content.
나는 완전히 만족합니다.
Thank you all.
모두 감사합니다.
[Longevity, Happy Birthday to My Dear Mother]
[장수, 사랑하는 어머니의 생일을 축하드립니다]
Mom, happy birthday.
엄마, 생일 축하해요.
Cheers.
건배.
-Happy birthday.
-생일 축하해요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I wish you good health.
나는 당신에게 건강을 기원합니다.
How come Mom knows it's a boy?
엄마는 그게 남자인 걸 어떻게 알았나요?
Everyone, let's eat.
여러분, 식사하세요.
Please help yourselves.
스스로 도와주세요.
This Purong Hotel
이 푸롱 호텔
is indeed magnificent.
정말 훌륭합니다.
I've always wanted to come in and take a look.
난 항상 들어오고 싶었어 그리고 한번 보세요.
Thanks to you,
고마워요
I can do so today.
오늘은 그렇게 할 수 있어요.
Not at all.
별말씀을요.
This is just a small gesture from the younger ones.
이건 작은 몸짓일 뿐이야 어린 것부터.
Mr. Nie.
니에 씨.
Mr. Wei.
웨이 씨.
Welcome to our hotel.
저희 호텔에 오신 것을 환영합니다.
It's very nice of you to say that.
그렇게 말씀해주셔서 정말 기쁩니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
This room is well decorated.
이 방은 잘 꾸며져 있어요.
Thanks for your hard work.
당신의 노고에 감사드립니다.
Let me make an introduction.
소개를하겠습니다.
This is the head of Purong Hotel,
푸롱호텔 대표입니다
Mr. Wei Siyuan.
웨이시위안 씨.
Don't call me the head.
나를 머리라고 부르지 마세요.
I'm just the chief butler,
나는 단지 수석 집사일 뿐이야,
aiming at serving everyone.
모두에게 봉사하는 것을 목표로 합니다.
What chief butler?
무슨 집사요?
You are just the head.
당신은 단지 머리입니다.
Mr. Wei,
웨이 씨,
nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
This is my mother.
이 분은 우리 어머니예요.
You can call me Wei.
웨이라고 불러주세요.
Mrs. Nie,
니 부인
today, it's my great honor
오늘은 정말 영광이에요
that you can celebrate your birthday
생일을 축하할 수 있게 됐어
in our hotel.
우리 호텔에서.
I have to drink a toast to you properly.
나는 당신에게 제대로 건배를 마셔야합니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
-Thank you, Mr. Wei. -May you...
- 고마워요, 웨이 씨. - 혹시...
Remain happy every day just like today,
오늘처럼 매일매일 행복하게 지내세요
and stay young forever.
영원히 젊음을 유지하세요.
Mr. Wei, it's very kind of you to say that.
웨이 씨, 정말 친절하시네요 그렇게 말하다니.
Please drink as you prefer.
원하는대로 마셔주세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Have a seat.
앉으세요.
Come on. Refill my glass.
어서 해봐요. 내 잔을 채워주세요.
Come on, Mr. Nie.
자, 니에 씨.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Let me drink a toast to you individually.
여러분께 개별적으로 건배를 드리도록 하겠습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Mr. Nie here
니에 씨 여기요
is a true winner in life.
인생의 진정한 승리자입니다.
He really deserves this reputation.
그는 정말 이런 평판을 받을 자격이 있습니다.
Thanks for your kind words.
당신의 친절한 말에 감사드립니다.
Let's move forward together.
함께 앞으로 나아가자.
Cheers.
건배.
Alright. Since this is a family feast,
괜찮은. 가족 잔치니까
I won't disturb you any longer.
더 이상 방해하지 않겠습니다.
Please forgive us
용서해주세요
if there's any oversight in our service.
당사 서비스에 감독이 있는 경우.
Kaixin, stay here and take good care of them.
카이신, 여기 남아서 그들을 잘 돌봐주세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Please enjoy your meal.
맛있게 드시기 바랍니다.
I'm leaving now.
나는 지금 떠난다.
Mom, I'll see him out.
엄마, 제가 그 사람을 찾아갈게요.
Mr. Wei.
웨이 씨.
Here's the thing.
여기에 문제가 있습니다.
From now on,
이제부터
please take good care of my wife.
내 아내를 잘 돌봐주세요.
You know what?
그거 알아?
She'll join your sales department in a few days.
그녀는 당신의 영업 부서에 합류할 것이다 며칠 안에.
I think we should treat you to dinner.
내 생각엔 우리가 당신에게 저녁을 대접해야 할 것 같아요.
You have to do us the honor.
당신은 우리에게 영광을 돌려야합니다.
Of course I'll take good care of her.
물론 내가 그녀를 잘 돌볼 것이다.
It's no big deal.
별거 아닙니다.
I'll ask Qian Xun to guide her.
Qian Xun에게 안내를 부탁하겠습니다.
Thanks a lot.
정말 감사합니다.
Not at all. We're old friends.
별말씀을요. 우리는 오랜 친구입니다.
I'll get going then.
그럼 바로 갈게요.
By the way...
그런데...
Um...
음...
How's it going with Kuanli?
관리 씨는 잘 지내요?
Is it confirmed?
확인됐나요?
Yes, it is.
예, 그렇습니다.
After Purong is entrusted to Kuanli,
푸롱이 관리에 맡겨진 후,
it'll only earn more profits.
더 많은 이익을 얻을 수 있을 뿐입니다.
Don't worry. If your wife works in my hotel,
괜찮아요. 당신의 아내가 내 호텔에서 일한다면,
she won't be at a disadvantage.
그녀는 불이익을 당하지 않을 것입니다.
-Okay, okay. -Alright. I'm leaving.
-알았어, 알았어. -괜찮은. 나는 떠난다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Hello, welcome.
안녕하세요, 환영합니다.
How many people?
몇 명입니까?
Just one.
딱 하나.
Okay. This way, please.
좋아요. 이쪽으로 부탁드립니다.
Mr. Ji?
지 씨?
What a coincidence.
정말 우연이군요.
-It's nice to see you here. -Mr. Nie.
- 여기서 만나서 반가워요. -씨. 니에.
Are you back from abroad for a vacation?
휴가차 해외에서 돌아오셨나요?
I'm just taking a few days off.
저는 며칠만 쉬고 있어요.
Have you received the email?
이메일을 받으셨나요?
Yes, I have.
예, 그렇습니다.
Thank you so much.
매우 감사합니다.
Let me report it to you.
당신에게 보고하겠습니다.
We've already started working on
우리는 이미
the luxury wilderness desert route.
작업을 시작했습니다. 럭셔리한 황야의 사막 루트.
The most critical thing now
지금 가장 중요한 것은
is to wait for you to resume work.
당신이 일을 재개할 때까지 기다리는 것입니다.
And then we can sync up.
그런 다음 동기화할 수 있습니다.
No need to wait for me.
나를 기다릴 필요가 없습니다.
I've alreday informed those several
나는 이미 그 몇몇에게 알려줬어요
department directors below me.
내 아래 부서장들.
They'll fully cooperate
그들은 전적으로 협력할 거야
with your proposal at any time.
언제든지 귀하의 제안과 함께.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Thank you very much.
매우 감사합니다.
Are you here to eat?
식사하러 오셨나요?
I'm just here to grab a quick bite.
난 그냥 간단히 한 입 먹으러 왔을 뿐이에요.
Look.
바라보다.
There's no time like the present.
지금과 같은 때는 없습니다.
This is a good chance for us to have a meal together.
이건 우리에게 좋은 기회야 같이 식사하려고.
A few colleagues of mine are here,
내 동료 몇 명이 여기 있어요
so we can even have a chat.
그래서 우리는 대화도 할 수 있어요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Take a small bite.
조금 먹어보세요.
You didn't expect there would be so many people, did you?
당신은 기대하지 않았다 사람이 정말 많을 텐데요, 그렇죠?
Mom.
엄마.
A friend of mine is here.
내 친구가 여기 있어요.
My mom and dad.
우리 엄마와 아빠.
Hello, Mr. and Mrs. Nie.
안녕하세요, 니에씨 부부입니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
These are all my relatives.
이들은 모두 내 친척입니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Let me introduce my colleagues.
동료들을 소개하겠습니다.
My assistant, Zhao Keqi.
나의 조수, 자오커치(Zhao Keqi).
Feng Bin and Liu Minghui.
펑빈과 류밍휘.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Let me formally
공식적으로 말해줘
introduce this gentleman.
이 신사를 소개해주세요.
Svelto Hotel Group,
스벨토 호텔 그룹,
Ji Feng.
지펑.
Welcome!
환영!
Mr. Ji.
지 씨.
Here, Mr. Ji.
저기, 지 씨.
Let me introduce myself first.
먼저 제 소개를 하겠습니다.
I'm the director of the HSKP Department of this hotel,
나는 감독이다 이 호텔 HSKP 부서의
Feng Kaixin.
펑 카이신.
Mr. Feng.
펑 씨.
Mr. Ji, you're well-known overseas.
지 선생님, 해외에서도 유명하신 분이세요.
As this is my first time meeting you,
당신을 처음 만나는 것이기 때문에
let me drink a toast to you.
당신을 위해 건배를 드리겠습니다.
I'll drink it up first.
먼저 마실게요.
You're already drinking.
당신은 이미 술을 마시고 있습니다.
You haven't even eaten yet.
당신은 아직 식사도 하지 않았습니다.
You can really hold your liquor!
정말 술을 담을 수 있어요!
Come on. Let me refill your glass.
어서 해봐요. 잔을 다시 채워 드리겠습니다.
That's enough.
그것으로 충분합니다.
You can drink later.
나중에 마셔도 됩니다.
What's the rush?
서두르는 이유는 무엇입니까?
Bring another chair here.
여기 의자 하나 더 가져오세요.
This is my fault.
이건 내 잘못이야.
I'll arrange it right away.
바로 정리하겠습니다.
Okay. Thank you.
좋아요. 감사합니다.
-Waiter. -This way.
-웨이터. - 이쪽으로.
Waiter!
웨이터!
Why don't you take my seat?
내 자리에 앉는 게 어때요?
How can we let you give your seat to the guest?
우리가 어떻게 당신을 허락할 수 있습니까? 손님에게 자리를 양보하시겠습니까?
Your health is important.
당신의 건강은 중요합니다.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
Who is this?
이 사람은 누구입니까?
My wife, Zhenzhen.
내 아내 젠젠.
I'm Lu Zhenzhen,
저는 루 젠젠이에요
Mr. Ji.
지 씨.
Mrs. Nie.
니에 부인.
-Congratulations, Mr. Nie. -Thank you.
-니에 씨, 축하드립니다. -감사합니다.
Sit.
앉다.
Coming.
오는.
Just squeeze in.
그냥 꽉 쥐어보세요.
Um...
음...
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Let me explain it to you all.
여러분 모두에게 설명해 드리겠습니다.
In this banquet hall,
이 연회장에서는
there are two wedding parties.
결혼식 파티가 두 번 있어요.
The waiters have all gone to help.
웨이터들이 모두 도와주러 갔습니다.
But it doesn't matter.
그러나 그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
I've arranged for an attendant from our HSKP Department.
나는 도우미를 준비했다 우리 HSKP 부서에서.
She will be here shortly.
그녀는 곧 여기에 올 것이다.
Do the attendants from the HSKP Department
HSKP 부서의 직원을 수행
know the restaurant's rules?
그 식당의 규칙을 아시나요?
I've transferred
전학했어
the best attendant from our executive floor.
최고의 수행자 우리 임원 층에서.
She can learn fast.
그녀는 빨리 배울 수 있습니다.
There will be absolutely no problem.
전혀 문제가 없을 것입니다.
I'm really sorry
정말 미안해요
to cause you trouble.
당신에게 문제를 일으키기 위해.
Not at all.
별말씀을요.
Alright. Let's eat.
괜찮은. 먹자.
Come on. Let's eat.
어서 해봐요. 먹자.
Ask the attendant-on-duty of the executive floor to come here now.
담당직원에게 물어보세요 지금 여기로 오실 임원 층의.
Hurry up!
서둘러요!